When we're thinking about a simple vending machine it's easy to enumerate the states.
我们很容易考虑出一台简单的自动售货机的状态
Now let's consider the states we may want to model for car driving on a highway.
现在 我们来考虑在高速路上的汽车 我们如何为其状态建模
Benny, let's just throw out all the ideas we can come up with and then prune the list
首先 我们先抛开那些很容易想到的东西
afterwards so we can show how we might think about
然后从头开始展示
coming up with a finite state machine from scratch.
我们如何去定义一个有限状态机
Okay, let's keep it simple first.
好了 我们先简化考虑
What happens if we are the only car on the road?
如果路上只有一辆车会如何？
I guess we would need a state for normal staying in your lane driving.
我猜想 我们会得出一个在车道上行驶的正常停留状态
If we are changing lanes,
那么 如果我们要变换车道
we want a state to represent that.
我们希望有一个状态来代表它
Or maybe two states since changing lanes to the left is different than to the right.
也许有两个状态 因为可以向左或者向右来变换
Okay. I guess. What changes if there's a vehicle in front of us?
还有 如果我们前方有一辆车 该怎么办？
Well we might want to stay behind it,
大概最好是待在它后面
so we should have a state for that or we might want to pass it.
那么也许我们需要一个用来超车的状态
I suppose, but isn't
不过 我估计并不需要
pass just a lane change to the left and then a lane change to the right?
因为超车可以看做是先向左换道 然后再向右换道
Do we really need in your state for that?
我们真的需要超车状态吗？
Hey, we're brainstorming no bad ideas.
哈 我们头脑风暴出很好的点子
Okay, fine. Well, what changes if we had more cars?
不错 很好 那么 如果有多辆车 该做哪些更改？
I could imagine in this situation you might want to slow down so that you
我能想到 在这种情况下 你也许想要减速
could merge into this gap here and then pass this car if it's going slow.
然后你就能够 插入这个空档 然后超过这辆车 如果它行驶不快
We should really have a slow downstate
我们应该有个减速状态
which I guess means we will also need a speed upstate.
这也就意味着我们也需要一个加速状态
We should probably add a stop state in case there is some emergency situation.
我们同样需要一个停止状态 因为也许会有紧急状况
I guess we could do all of that at once by having a keep target speed state.
我想大家马上就会想到我们还应该有个保持目标车速的状态
Well I don't know.
但是我现在也不太清楚
Shouldn't speed just be dictated by the lane you're driving in and the speed limit?
车辆速度仅仅应该由该车行驶的车道和限速来决定？
What if we just add a prepare lane change state to represent when
如果我们为准备变道插入空档的 ego 车
the ego vehicle is trying to go next to an empty gap in traffic before a lane change?
定义一个准备换道状态会怎么样？
Yeah, that could work but we should probably have
是的 那似乎可行 不过我们或许应该
a prepare lane change left and to prepare a lane change right,
先准备向左换道然后再准备向右换道
since those really are different maneuvers.
因为他们是完全不同的动作
Oh, and we could also turn on the turn signals down.
然后 我们也会有打开指示灯和熄灭指示灯的动作
Good point. The truth is there isn't a single correct set of states to choose from.
不错的点子 事实上 并不存在一套完全正确的状态集让大家选择
On one hand we want to keep our state space as small as
一方面 我们想要最小状态空间
possible for maintainability reasons,
以方便维护
but on the other hand we want to make sure we have enough logical States
但是另一方面 我们希望我们可以有足够的状态空间
to actually represent all the physical states that we care about.
来代表我们关心的所有物理状态
As you've seen in the discussion we've just had it's
就如我们刚讨论过的
not easy to find the perfect set of states for this scenario.
对于这个场景 找出完美的状态集并不容易
Why don't you think for a minute about what states you would want
为什么大家不花点时间考虑下
to use to represent vehicle behavior on a highway.
在高速公路上行驶的车辆的状态
Check the boxes next to each state that you'd keep and
请大家勾选每个状态旁边的选择框
write any additional ones in the empty boxes on the left.
并且在左边的空框里面写出任何其他的状态